daytonastate.edu 2016-04-02

# Untitled Document

**Commitment to Your Privacy**  
Protecting your personal privacy is a priority at Daytona State. We are committed to safeguarding the personal information you share with us. This Privacy Policy tells you how your personal information is used by the College, and we pledge to take the appropriate steps to ensure your personal information is used only in ways that are compatible with this Privacy Policy.

**Information We Gather**  
Daytona State collects both personal and non-personal information on our site. When a visitor completes a college application, scholarship application or other online form we collect such items as name, address, e-mail address, and date of birth. This data is collected and transmitted securely and housed in our college systems for processing. The information you provide is confidential and will only be used to develop our business relationship with you and meet your requests. No information provided by you or details of any business transactions are sold to any third party. Data is shared with third parties only when necessary to process a transaction, or to comply with appropriate laws and regulations.

Certain non-personal information is collected when you browse our web site, read pages or download information. This information does not identify you personally. It is collected to help us improve our web site and general services to the public. The items we gather will include the internet domain and address of the computer accessing the site, the type of browser or other client application used, the operating system of the computer, the web pages visited, the referring web pages and the time spent on our site. Cookies are also used by our site for session management.

**Third-party Web Sites**  
Daytona State's Web site provides links to a wide variety of other web sites. Daytona State is not responsible for the content of these third party sites, and their privacy policies will vary. Daytona State encourages you to be aware when you leave the Daytona State web site and carefully read the privacy statements of any web site that collects personally identifiable information.

**Updates and Questions**  
Daytona State reserves the right, at its discretion, to change this policy at any time.  Please check back periodically for updates.

Contact us with any questions at [web_services@daytonastate.edu](mailto:web_services@daytonastate.edu "Web Support")  
Send mail to:  
Daytona State College  
Attention: Web Services  
1200 West International Speedway Boulevard  
Daytona Beach, FL 32119

**Notice to students regarding the downloading and distribution of copyrighted material.**

Daytona State College does not monitor file sharing activities on its network. Institutions that protect the rights of the record companies and owners, such as the Recording Industry Association of America (RIAA) and Motion Picture Association of America (MPAA), the Business Software Alliance (BSA), and the Entertainment Software Association (ESA) among others, monitor illegal downloading, copying or sharing of music, videos, commercial software and computer games using file sharing programs across the Internet. 

When a copyright violation is discovered, copyright holders or their agents will report the alleged infringement to the Internet Service Provider (ISP) where the IP address is registered. The College is required to respond to complaints from copyright holders, and organizations representing copyright holders, regarding computers on campus that are illegally distributing copyrighted materials. Copyright holders or their agents will request that the College identify the owner of the machine associated with the reported IP address and relay the Takedown or DMCA Notice to the alleged copyright infringer and/or coordinate the removal of access to the infringing content.

Daytona State College could receive a number of notices related to the copyright infringement or be served with subpoenas from an agency representing the copyright holder. The following are the most common copyright infringement notices sent from organizations representing copyright holders:

**Frequently Asked Questions**

  * **How do I know if something is copyrighted?**
    * Most music, videos, lyrics, books, TV shows, etc. are copyrighted. You would be better to assume that everything is copyrighted unless you know specifically otherwise.
  * **What can happen to me if I violate copyright laws?**
    * Under copyright law, violators can be held liable for a minimum of $750 per violation (each file is a single violation), so it costs the students thousands of dollars to settle the lawsuits out of court. A copyright violation is legally known as "strict liability", which means your knowledge or intent to perform an illegal act is not necessary for you to be liable. If the violations exceed $2,500 in penalties, and if the RIAA or MPAA could prove you had actual intent to violate their copyrights, criminal sanctions could be pursued. Criminal sanctions for copyright violations carry a penalty of up to $250,000 and the possibility of up to five years in prison.
  * **What applications are used for illegal downloading?**
    * Gnutella, Limewire, Morpheus, BitTorrent, Ares, Aimster, Bearshare, Kazaa, Imesh and Napster are a few of the more common names from over the years. There are dozens and dozens of applications that fall into this category. Having LimeWire, KaZaA, Blubster, Grokster, BitTorrent, Gnutella, iMesh,CuteMX, Scour, FreeNetfile or any other music or movie file-sharing software on your computer opens the door to liability. While file-sharing software may itself be lawful, there is usually a copyright on the music, video or other files being shared. Unless the copyright owner gives explicit written permission, file sharing is a violation of copyright law.
  * **What about "fair use"?**
    * Fair use covers things like making a copy of a purchased CD for use in your MP3 player or car. It does not allow you to download music for free that you would normally have to purchase.
